

STEVEN LEE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGIEER

stevenL

Strong, skillful, and self-organized software engineer with 9 years experience of developing web and mobile applications, optimizing the existing environments. Having strong background and good understanding of code concepts, application development optimization, and performance tuning

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGIEER

Southwest Airlines

09/2022 - Present

- Work on the airline booking and service system by leveraging React.js and TypeScript on mobile web environment.
- Improve the performance of the frontend by following several scenarios - code splitting, optimizing API calls and re-renders, SSR, SEO and etc...
- Perform the code review for peers and collaborate with cross functional teams in iteration planning to refine stories in every sprint.
- worked actively in Agile and Scrum environments with 2-week sprints.

SENIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

Cisco

08/2020 - 07/2022

- Made architectural decisions of the Frontend Repo to meet business requirements.
- Implemented the state management system by utilizing Redux Thunk and React Context.
- Introduced Custom React Hook functions to improve reusability and readability.

347-632-8928

 \checkmark

steven.lee0287@gmail.com



1251Turk St., San Francisco

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY

Empire State University

Computer Science 2012 - 2015

SKILLS

- React, React Native, Redux, Next,
 Angular, Vue, Sass/LESS, Tailwind,
 AWS, Azure, Figma, Docker
- GraphQL, REST API, Node, Express, Nest, Django, RoR, AWS EC2, S3, Lamda, GCP, Postgres, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, Jest, Cypress, Jenkins
- Solidity, Rust, Go, web3.js, ethers.js, MetaMask, NFT, DAO, DeFi, Dapp, Swap, ETH, BNB, MATIC, BTC, USDC

FRONT END DEVELOPER

Attain, Inc.

06/2016 - 08/2020

- Continuously enhanced new features and debugged & troubleshooted bugs arising while running the project by utilizing HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React.js under Agile/Scrum team based on 2 weeks sprints.
- Work on the airline booking and service system by leveraging React.js and TypeScript on mobile web environment.
- Improve the performance of the frontend by following several scenarios - code splitting, optimizing API calls and re-renders, SSR, SEO and etc...
- Perform the code review for peers and collaborate with cross functional teams in iteration planning to refine stories in every sprint.
- worked actively in Agile and Scrum environments with 2-week sprints.

JUNIOR FRONT END DEVELOPER

Attain, Inc.

10/2015 - 05/2016

- Used PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, MySQL
- Developed responsive design using Flex & Grid CSS for web and mobile
- Worked with team members under Agile Scrum methodology

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY

Empire State University

Computer Science 2012 - 2015

SKILLS

- React, React Native, Redux, Next,
 Angular, Vue, Sass/LESS, Tailwind,
 AWS, Azure, Figma, Docker
- GraphQL, REST API, Node, Express, Nest ,Django, RoR, AWS EC2, S3, Lamda, GCP, Postgres, MongoDB, DynamoDB, Docker, Kubernetes, Azure, Jest, Cypress, Jenkins
- Solidity, Rust, Go, web3.js, ethers.js,
 MetaMask, NFT, DAO, DeFi, Dapp,
 Swap, ETH, BNB, MATIC, BTC,
 USDC